# 你看 圆圆乎乎了吧
See? They are spherical now
# 大团子 还真光溜啊
Big steamed buns. The surface is really smooth.
# 就用这种办法 保证薄皮儿大馅儿
In this way, you can definitely get the buns with thin skin and full stuffing
# 有很多网友说这菜团子怎么包
Some friends asked me how to make steamed vegetable buns
# 我创造了一个新的手法
I invented a new technique
# 其实我也包不是特别专业
Actually I am not very professional in making buns
# 我们家是这样
In my home, it was like this
# 这个棒子面要烫棒子面
The cornmeal... You need to add boiling water
# 烫一半留一半
Mix half of the cornmeal with boiling water and keep the other half
# 大爷一瞧很专业啊
That looks professional, Da Ye
# 你看 二伯也懂
Er Bai knows this as well
# 烫一半
Mix half of the cornmeal with boiling water
# 今天这棒子面就比较细
The cornmeal here is very fine
# 还筋道
and somewhat tough
# 好了 这就可以了
Ok. That's done
# 但是我们还要搁一些凉水
But we still need to add some cold water
# 把它和匀了 和滋润了
To mix it up until it looks shiny
# 热水烫起到了决定性作用 黏糊了
Boiling water is the key. It's sticky now
# 以前特别逗
This is a funny story
# 十几岁我就会包这个菜团子
I could make this when I was a teenager
# 07年 大妈特别想吃个菜团子
In 2007, Da Ma really wanted to have this dish
# 完了以后我说没问题
I said, "No problem!"
# 我给你包个菜团子保证是薄皮大馅
"Let me make it for you. I am sure it must be full of stuffing with thin skin"
# 想吃我说包一个吧
Then I made some (steamed vegetable buns)
# 是棒子面的问题
I didn't know if the problem was with the cornmeal
# 是我的手艺问题
or my cooking skill
# 一包一裂口 一包一裂口
There were crackings on each of them!
# 然后我就拿面补
Then I filled the crackings with wheat flour
# 越补这面 这团子越大
But the steamed buns were getting bigger and bigger
# 咬了一口没咬着馅
You could not even touch the stuffing on your first bite
# 我们家老伴说了 瞧你这吹
My wife was like, 'You must be bluffing!'
# 隋坡再给我来点水 好嘞
Sui Po, get me some more water. Ok!
# 但是我还是不死心
But I didn't give up
# 过几天我说我再给你包一回
Several days later, I told her that I would make the buns again
# 这回保证薄皮大馅
I promised that they would be full of stuffing with thin skin
# 我创造了一个新的手法
I invented a new technique
# 是哪儿启发了我呢
What inspired me?
# 一会我给大家展示一下
I will show you later
# 这个面好了 然后让它饧一饧
The cornmeal is ready. Leave it to rest
# 下一步咱弄馅
Let's prepare the stuffing next
# 你看 这个红皮萝卜
Look. The red-skin radish here
# 我们常说的叫卞萝卜
We also refer to it as 'Bian' radish
# 这是个大圆的
This is a round one
# 这儿就用这个萝卜来擦的丝
These shreds are from the radish
# 这胡萝卜也是擦
Use the kitchen shredder to shred the carrot as well
# 这个是略焯 不要焯太大发了
Blanch it shortly. Do not blanch for too long
# 略焯
Just a little while
# 好了
Done
# 冲凉
Rinse with cold water
# 你看胡萝卜白萝卜出完水了 冲凉了
After rinsing the shredded radish with water
# 给它挤挤水
Squeeze the water out
# 木耳
Black wood ear mushroom
# 这个蛋皮丝可以
Shredded fried egg
# 也可以炒点碎碎的鸡蛋
You can replace it with eggs that are fried into tiny bits
# 二伯 来
Er bai, come on
# 把萝卜丝揽两刀
Simply chop the shredded radish
# 看着啊 粉丝准备好了 油也热了
Look. The vermicelli is ready. The oil is also hot
# 看见了吧 特别简单
See that? Very simple
# 这就好了 再来
This is done. Again
# 就搁这儿就行
Place it here
# 一会儿给它斩一斩
Let' s cut it later
# 或者让它晾一晾拿手一揉
Or cool it down and crush with your hand
# 炸完以后它就已经熟了
It's already cooked after frying
# 还香呢炸完了
It also smells better
# 你看拿刀轻轻一斩
Look. Simply chop it with the knife
# 在素馅里边 这粉丝是必须要给的
In vegetable stuffing, you must have vermicelli
# 为什么呢 有的素菜它会出水
Why? Some vegetables may be juicy and will give out moisture
# 出水怎么办 搁点粉丝
How to deal with that? Add some vermicelli
# 另外它还产生了香气
Also the vermicelli enhances the aroma
# 好了 现在要调味了
Good. Now let's season it
# 素馅调味的不加酱油
Soy sauce does not go well with vegetable stuffing
# 先把盐加上 这盐要不能少
Add salt first. Not too little
# 因为团子（有面）
Since the buns (are made of cornmeal and are bland)
# 一勺不够 两勺 两勺半盐
One teaspoon is not enough. Two, two and a half teaspoons of salt
# 盐搁完了 白胡椒
After the salt, white pepper powder
# 香油
Sesame oil
# 馅儿一好 咱就开始了
Let's start when the stuffing is ready
# 来 二伯给倒上 倒点味精
Come on, Er Bai. Add some MSG
# 手拌馅是最快的 而且还拌的匀
It's the fastest to mix the stuffing with your hands. Also it can be mixed more evenly.
# 来点葱姜
Some ginger and green onion
# 还得来点油吗 来油啊
Some more oil? Yes, please
# 还得炼点儿油呢
Let's prepare some oil as well
# 搁点葱尾巴 香葱
Some green onion leaves. Scallion
# 香菜 搁个大料
Coriander. A star anise
# 还很香这个油 很香 再搁点料油
The oil is very aromatic. Some more oil please
# 我还得讲刚才的故事 接着讲
Let me continue to tell my previous story
# 我就奇怪了
I was wondering
# 我说我现在厨艺有点下降了
I was like, 'Does my cooking skill deteriorate?'
# 后来我想了个诀窍 什么诀窍呢
Later on I invented a trick. What was it?
# 有一次 正好什么启发了我呢
There was one time... when I was inspired
# 包一个一斤半的狮子头
Making a 750-g Shi Zi Tou (Literally lion head, braised pork ball in brown sauce)
# 里边还要上馅儿 谁也包不上去
We needed to put stuffing inside as well. No one could do it
# 我忽然间就启发了
It suddenly came to my mind that
# 找一个保鲜膜找一大碗
I found a piece of plastic wrap and a big bowl
# 把肉馅打好了以后铺在保鲜膜上
Placed the minced meat on the plastic wrap
# 给它抹圆乎了抹均匀了
Spreaded it evenly
# 然后把炒好的素馅装进去
Then placed cooked vegetable stuffing inside
# 这是一斤（肉）馅儿啊
That was 500 grams of minced meat
# 然后再称了半斤馅儿
Then I got 250 more grams of minced meat
# 再把底儿一封 拿保鲜膜一兜
to seal the bottom. Then I wrapped up the plastic wrap
# 二伯 这么大一狮子头
Er Bai, the lion head was like this big
# 包的好好的光溜溜的
It was perfect and smooth
# 我就想起这个来了
This inspired me
# 今天呢
Today
# 我这个方法给大家重现一下
I will show you this technique
# 你看找一个合适的碗
Look. Find a right bowl
# 把这面搁里头
Put the cornmeal inside
# 首先要把碗底儿的皮给它抹的均匀
Make sure the skin underneath is even in thickness
# 你看看 都已经成一碗状了
Look. It already looks like a bowl
# 这时候我们往里边盛馅儿
Let's add stuffing now
# 这个菜团子的馅儿得足实
You need enough stuffing for the steamed bun
# 你看啊 装好了吧
See that? The bun is filled with stuffing
# 一起一提了 出来了
Lift it up. Out of the bowl
# 首先我相信我底下这个皮儿是薄的
Firstly, I am sure that the skin at the bottom is thin
# 然后我们一点一点的
Then let's seal it, little-by-little
# 拢的时候手里沾点水
Apply some water in your hand
# 要不它粘的哪儿都是 馅儿都跑了
Otherwise it's gonna stick to everywhere. The stuffing will be gone
# 一边拢着一边蹲
Close it slowly while 'sitting' it to the bottom
# 越蹲越收口
The opening will be closed as you 'sit' it
# 那天我看什么大饼 肉饼
I was watching (others making) meat pies the other day
# 那疙瘩面不很多 那块肉可不少
I noticed that the dough was small, but there was a lot of meat
# 三团两团
But somehow, as he 'sat' the meat stuffing into the dough
# 把这一大块肉给团进去了
The whole pile of meat stuffing was closed in the skin
# 二伯看见了吧 你看你看
Er Bai, see that?
# 这口越来越小
The opening is getting smaller and smaller
# 这得有耐心 大爷的耐心够大的
You need to be patient. Da Ye has great patience
# 一点一点
Little by little
# 你看也不漏
Look, no cracking
# 圆圆乎乎的吧
They are round now
# 上锅了 一开锅十五分钟
Into the pot. 15 minutes after boiling
# 得嘞 我看时间 您歇会
Okay. I'll keep an eye on the time and you can have a rest
# 二伯 蒸了十五分钟
Er Bai. Steamed for 15 minutes,
# 闷了有一分多钟
rest with the lid closed for about 1-2 minutes
# 薄皮大馅 走着
Full stuffing, thin skin. Let's go!
# 还真光溜 不错
So smooth. Looks good
# 晾晾晾晾 下不了手
Cool it for a while. Can't touch it now
# 好啦 大团子
Done. Big steamed buns!
# 黄澄澄金灿灿的大团子
Golden yellow buns!
# 二伯先吃
Er Bai, take a bite first.
# 这面嚼起来还有点糯
The cornmeal is somewhat soft
# 关键什么
The key is
# 这馅儿的咸淡味拿捏的特别好
The savory taste is perfect
# 比馒头进去还舒服
Feels even better than steamed bread
# 谢谢二伯
Thank you, Er Bai
# 隋坡呢 我吃俩了都 饿了你是
-Sui Po, what about you? -I have had two already. - You must be hungry
# 难以形容的好吃
Unbelievably delicious
# 特别是二伯炸的料油搁里边
Especially, with Er Bai's aromatic oil
# 特别的香 油润润的
The steamed buns are so aromatic and smooth
# 料油的香味特别足
The aroma of the oil is so strong
# 一般咱们会噎嗓子
You might choke up on normal steamed buns
# 但是他这个出溜就下去了
But this one simply goes down your gullet
# 非常舒服 很滑
Very comfortable. So smooth
# 为你点赞 谢谢二伯 谢谢隋坡
Thumb up for you! Thanks, Er Bai! Thanks, Sui Po!
# 对不住了 中午我有饭了
Sorry about that. Got food for my lunch